=Remnants of Gold=
(Adapted from Gu Long's
"Flying Eagle over the Great Land")
(The main characters
in this drama are fictional)
=Episode 3=
(Zhang Escort Agency)
Why are you sleeping at the doorway?
The door wasn't even bolted.
What do you think?
What...
What can I say?
There are two women inside.
How was I supposed to go in at night?
It's broad daylight now.
(Notice: Zhang Escort Agency seeks
gold hunters. Reward: 100 taels of gold)
The capital of Ming must be wonderful.
Even out here in a border town,
you know men and
women should keep their distance.
I was a Banner Leader
in the Embroidered Uniform Guard
when I was 26.
That was Junior Seventh Rank.
It took five years to
rise half a rank to Banner Commander.
A Seventh Rank is nobody in the capital.
Who would've thought
that in this small border guard,
it still means nothing.
That's fine.
I just never expected
to be poisoned by a woman.
I had so many nightmares last night.
I rarely used to have nightmares before.
I barely even had good dreams.
You're still laughing?
What do you want
to do most in this life?
Get the antidote,
and then kill you.
You won't kill me.
Even if you get the antidote, you won't.
Why don't you cure me first and see?
I'm asking what you wanted
most before you were poisoned.
Tell me the truth.
Get rich.
Besides that?
Uphold justice.
Getting rich and upholding justice...
If you could only
choose one between the two?
Why should I tell you the truth?
You can ask me questions, too.
All your 27 family members are dead.
How are you still in
the mood to wash your hair here?
You're a good man.
Poisoning you was the right choice.
I am an imperial official
of the Seventh Rank.
Not even the Commander-in-Chief of
Gansu, General Pingxi, would touch me.
As long as you listen to me,
I will give you the antidote.
Won't you be afraid of dying then?
I've already died many times.
I won't die again.
No one even knows
you poisoned me right now.
This is too much.
Give me the antidote.
Speak softly.
Don't get agitated.
Breathe.
Three times.
Head west...
You're the only one I can trust.
Why should I go west with you?
Don't you want to get
rich and uphold justice?
Head west,
and you will get
both wealth and justice.
Do you still feel like
a woman to yourself?
That's the question you asked me?
There's no woman like you in this world.
How should I be then?
Your family is dead.
Don't you know how to cry?
Put it that way,
I really don't seem like one.
Five years ago,
when I fell off the cliff on Shu Road,
I cried away a lifetime of tears
over three days and nights.
I realized crying was useless.
Desperate men are here.
I'll comb my hair first.
Officer Pu, please go ask them first.
Ask what?
Test their skills,
see if they're obedient,
and how much gold they want.
We only have 200 taels.
I'll go ask?
What is the meaning of this?
This is my horse and my stuff.
This is crossing the line.
Even petty thieves
dare to mess with me now?
Get down!
Get down.
Get down, do you hear me?
Zhang Luyao!
Get down.
(Notice: Seek For Gold Hunters)
I'm here to join.
Who are you?
Embroidered Uniform Guard.
Get down.
Who's that over there?
Who?
Sir.
Is this the Zhang Escort Agency?
Yes.
The one where many people died?
Who are you?
I'm Fang.
I'm here to apply.
They said there's gold.
Including this,
we've already given you 570 taels.
Two hundred taels went to the Zhangs.
My men and I didn't get much.
Yu Hou,
the Embroidered Uniform Guard officer
from the capital
didn't even accept those 200 taels.
Looks like we hit a coward.
The Zhang lady's journey west
has drawn out the guardians of the gold.
My men and I
will put in even more work from here on.
This amount of gold
is not enough.
Futu,
the General has already
given you plenty of gold.
Why isn't the General using
the Ganzhou Guard troops?
Over 100,000 men are on the payroll.
The General wouldn't need to pay extra.
Shouldn't you add a bit more?
That's for
the Commander-in-Chief to decide.
I'll go ask the General.
My name is Zhang Luyao.
She's Pingping.
And Officer Pu
is an Embroidered Uniform Guard from
the capital sent to investigate a case.
Everyone calls me Lamp Shade.
I'm Fang.
Officer Pu,
do you have other
urgent matters to attend to?
This matter is the most important.
What else is there?
That's good.
Heading west leads to death.
Many have already been poisoned
and died, turning into vengeful ghosts.
Did you know that?
We know.
As long as there's gold to earn.
If you are the only ones here
who aren't afraid to die,
it's 200 taels of gold, 100 taels each.
No one else wanted to come.
They were all
afraid of losing their lives.
If only one of you is left,
you won't have to split the 200 taels.
I didn't come just for the gold.
Then what for?
Everyone knows your family
was killed by bandits.
I came to help.
I'll do whatever you tell me to do.
You don't want the gold?
I do.
Are you good at martial arts?
Yes.
Don't take 100 taels each just yet.
Test your skills.
Let's see who can take all 200 taels.
There's no need for all that.
Miss, can we stop fighting?
I don't need that much gold.
You don't want it, but does he?
I'll split it with him.
Pingping,
go fetch some water
so he can wash his eyes.
Don't fight anymore!
(May Divine Might Protect Us Forever)
Two of my men died
at your place in the Liangzhou Guard,
and you didn't even lift a finger.
You let the last escort guard
be killed right in front of me.
With the victim present,
how could I act?
The victim?
The Zhang lady.
The General wants to use her
to lure out the guardians of the gold.
Your men
deserved to die.
Sooner or later,
you'll pay with your life.
General Ha.
Another 60 taels
to Futu.
I have a few words
I'd like to go in and ask the General.
The General took his medicine
and went to sleep.
What's wrong with the General?
The General is much better.
300,000 taels of gold
might just be a legend.
In Gansu's jurisdiction,
even if it's just a legend,
the General still
wants to figure it out.
The Zhang lady is no simple person.
So we asked her back.
So, kill her whole family
just to make her come back?
Yu Hou,
what's wrong with you?
I'm fine.
Look at me.
Yu Hou,
you and I have followed the General
for 20 years,
through hundreds of battles,
big and small.
I've never seen you like this before.
Maybe it's been too long
since I last saw the General.
If we can't use the Zhang lady
to find the guardians of the gold,
to avoid further trouble,
then she's of no use anymore.
She easily
cured the Embroidered
Uniform Guard's poison.
She must know where
the poison came from.
So,
she headed west alone.
That's good.
Have we planted our man among them?
Yes.
Is he obedient?
Completely obedient.
When she's no longer useful,
tell him
to kill her.
What does this mean?
Heading west tomorrow morning.
Heading west is clearly a dead end.
We put out one recruitment notice,
and two people showed up.
There are always people
risking their lives for money.
Don't you find that suspicious?
If an Embroidered Uniform Guard officer
hadn't come from the capital,
I wouldn't even know what to do next.
What do you want to do?
I need to find two enemies.
The person who placed the escort
order with my father and brother,
and the guardians of the gold.
The Zhang Escort Agency
mostly just escorts merchants.
If the client
already knew the whereabouts of
the 300,000 taels of gold,
with top martial artists
everywhere in the desert,
why would they hire the Zhangs?
Exactly.
Why?
The Zhangs took the job,
the guardians of the gold
poisoned and killed people,
and the client
killed the last escort master
of our agency to silence him.
When?
I happened to see it
while I was at Deputy Yu's residence.
The client didn't
know where the gold was.
They hired the Zhangs
so I would come back and
identify the poison for them.
I willingly tested poisons for 3 years
at the Tang Clan just to survive,
never expecting
it would bring disaster
upon my father and brother.
Among those two guys outside,
one of them is the person
who poisoned my family.
I couldn't figure out
where the poison came from,
so they had no choice
but to head west with me
to find the guardians of the gold.
Don't move your hand.
Open your eyes.
Open them.
Blink a bit.
Blink your eyes.
Is there still sand in it?
There's still some.
Are there any left?
Yes.
Liar.
Your eyes are bright
and quite clear now.
If you say it's gone,
then it's gone.
Hurry up and get up.
Officer Pu,
I'll investigate the murder,
and you arrest them.
How do I arrest them?
Go requisition some troops.
Requisition what troops?
Which one is the killer?
Once I interrogate them outside,
I'll make the arrest.
Given the skills of those two outside,
can you really make an arrest,
Officer Pu?
Miss Zhang, you can assist me.
Those who came are
just assassin mercenaries.
They have plenty of them,
and they're crawling with top masters.
The Liangzhou Guard Deputy Military
Commissioner is in league with them.
We can only rely on you
to requisition troops, Officer Pu.
Travel west for a day,
and arrest the killer at Heisong Post.
If you're scared, you may leave.
I will figure something else out.
Leave how?
You poisoned me.
If I wanted to leave,
I would've left long ago.
The 200 taels of gold belong to me.
If I were leaving,
why wouldn't I take the gold earlier?
Why?
Because they look down on me.
I came to investigate and catch
the murderer. Believe it or not?
I believe you.
Believe? And you poisoned me?
Would you believe me
if I told you
that I didn't poison you?
No.
I'll go get the troops.
Brat.
Where are you going, Officer Pu?
Do I really need to report to you?
You brat.
Who are you calling a brat?
Country bumpkin.
Officer Pu,
the Deputy is not here.
He's really not here.
Not here again?
You don't believe it?
Would you like to go inside and check?
Officer.
I need to requisition troops.
This is
the Embroidered Uniform Guard token.
Why do you need troops, Officer?
Besides the Deputy, is there anyone else
in charge of the Liangzhou Guard?
Why send a coroner to talk
to me every single time?
How many do you need, Officer?
Are you really a coroner?
The Liangzhou Guard fights
and guards the border. No extra hands.
My pay is on the register,
so I do the work for that pay.
At the same time,
I handle other matters for the Deputy.
I'll be staying
at Liangzhou Post tonight.
Lend me 20 guards.
Have them await my orders
in front of the post tomorrow morning.
Officer Pu has left.
Give him the men
from the 20th Residence.
Do not move the guards on the city wall.
Then there'll be no
one left at the residence.
The guards on the wall
have nothing to do anyway.
Coroner.
Understood.
You go along, too.
Deputy,
those two women from the Zhang family...
Isn't taking an escort job west
just seeking death?
In this great desert,
is there really 300,000 taels of gold?
If there's no gold,
why have so many people died?
Right?
You know Futu.
Who doesn't know Futu?
You will meet him.
Don't let those 20 guards
get in Futu's way.
Meaning, don't interfere
with Futu's business.
What if Officer Pu wants to do his job?
In this remote land,
we answer only to the General.
What are you doing? I'm Fang.
It's me.
Did you see...
Did you see anything?
What?
I've been waiting for you.
What were you up to,
sneaking around like that?
Nothing.
Nothing?
It really was nothing.
I saw you sneaking out all by yourself.
You didn't tell Luyao,
and you didn't tell me either.
Why would I need to tell you two?
If you won't tell us,
then don't come along with us tomorrow.
No, you can't do that.
I have gotten the gold.
I knew something was up with you.
We're leaving you behind.
Wait a second!
To relieve myself.
I went to relieve myself.
How can I talk
about that with women like you?
I had to take a dump.
Are you serious?
Of course, I am.
If you don't believe me,
I can take you to see it.
It's really close...
You're so annoying.
Officer.
Where are we going?
Just follow me, and that's that.
The Northwest is vast
and sparsely populated.
Do you know the way, Officer?
To
Heisong Post.
To get to Heisong Post,
you have to cross the Dry Gorge
and head west.
You're going the wrong way.
Keep up.
(Yu Residence)
What is it?
Do you never bolt your door?
The guards would
never barge in like that.
Not a single one of them is here.
Officer Pu borrowed them.
This is for you.
What is this?
On my trip west,
whether I live or die,
I will never return.
Everyone at
the Zhang Escort Agency is dead.
You're the official responsible
for the people of Liangzhou.
I'm giving you the deed to the agency.
For military use,
civilian use,
or whatever you see fit.
(Property Deed)
Even if you live, you won't come back?
Do you have family in Gansu?
The Commander-in-Chief was
like a father and brother to me.
If they were still alive,
this would be my home.
Now that my family is gone,
this is just Liangzhou.
If I survive,
please return to the Tang Clan
in Northern Shu.
I fought so hard to escape.
I won't go back.
You married into the Tang Clan...
Your husband is dead?
Have you ever seen a demon?
No, but I know
what a demon looks like.
I never saw my husband's face clearly.
But I know
demons look just like him.
You never saw him clearly?
He was translucent.
He used me to test
poisons for three years.
The Tang Clan
is heck.
Were you the person who poisoned
all 27 members of my family?
No.
I believe you.
I'll leave the silver bell
with you, too.
When Officer Pu was under the influence
of the poison for an hour,
his frenzy was gradually subsiding.
This ancient Western
Sichuan bell captivates the soul.
It can calm someone
who is wild or panicked
until their strength is spent.
Why give it to me?
Because your heart is filled with panic.
Won't you be needing it?
My heart is as still as water.
I have many dark thoughts in my heart,
but I've never dared to act on them.
Tired of the desert
and wanting to head south
is not a dark thought.
Worse than that.
Your family members are still alive.
Why not go talk to the General
about the things on your mind?
What if the General
harbored evil thoughts, too?
My father said
the Commander-in-Chief
is the deity of the Northwest.
Deities don't harbor evil thoughts.
I've never met anyone like you.
I'm leaving.
Farewell.
That Yuezhou guqin
is a fake from Fengyang.
It's very cheap.
It doesn't match your fine clothes.
It'll get hot once we
leave this narrow pass.
There won't be any shade
until Heisong Post.
We need to pick up the pace.
I can't walk fast.
If you're slow,
we won't make it to Heisong Post.
Do you all want to sleep in the sand?
I've never seen
so much sand and rock before.
Where are you from?
Shu.
Shu isn't as good as the Northwest.
Have you been there?
I don't care to.
Nowhere is better than the Northwest.
Why are you called Lamp Shade?
I forgot.
People started calling me that
a long time ago.
Where is the gold?
Who knows?
Tucked in the waistband.
How do you plan to spend 100 taels?
You've never thought about it, right?
No need to think.
How did you happen to be in Liangzhou?
I was traveling with a caravan.
I got sick,
so I stayed in Liangzhou
for half a month.
What kind of caravan?
Silk and tea leaves.
One hundred and twenty-six camels.
They headed east
from Liangzhou half a month ago.
Let's go.
Keep up.
Hurry!
(Preview of the Next Episode)
From now on,
people may enter the Post,
but no one leaves.
Who are you?
Bancha.
I do not lie.
That's hard for ordinary people to do.
You're no ordinary person.
Nine is almost at Heisong Post.
Every single one of you will die.
=Remnants of Gold=